<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><structure licence="1"><session1 SessionName="Course Introduction"><page length="59"><pgName>S1P1: Introduction</pgName></page></session1><quiz quizName="Managing Risk in Projects Demo Quiz" random="1" quizTotal="10" shortcuts="10" time="10"><Q1 answer="2"><category>1</category><question>In Discounted Cash-Flow, the IRR is the value of the discounting rate (r) which makes the Net Present Value equal to:</question><answer>The Break-Even Point</answer><answer>Zero</answer><answer>BCWP</answer><answer>The Total Budget</answer></Q1><Q2 answer="1"><category>1</category><question>The Standard Deviation for a set of data is:</question><answer>A Measure of Dispersion</answer><answer>A Measure of Central Tendency</answer><answer>A Figure of Merit</answer><answer>The Square Root of the Mean</answer></Q2><Q3 answer="4"><category>1</category><question>Risk Mitigation strategies can be divided into three categories: Risk Reduction, Contingency and ....</question><answer>Acceptance</answer><answer>Elimination</answer><answer>Avoidance</answer><answer>Transfer</answer></Q3><Q4 answer="2"><category>1</category><question>When bank interest rates are high, projects with low IRR&apos;s will become more attractive.</question><answer>True</answer><answer>False</answer></Q4><Q5 answer="4"><category>1</category><question>A DCF analysis has produced the following IRR figures for four competing projects. Which project is likely to be the most attractive?</question><answer>8%</answer><answer>18%</answer><answer>23%</answer><answer>34%</answer></Q5><Q6 answer="1"><category>1</category><question>If the probability of the best outcome occuring is 20% and the most likely is 75% - what will be the probability that the worst outcome happens?</question><answer>5%</answer><answer>10%</answer><answer>20%</answer><answer>25%</answer></Q6><Q7 answer="1"><category>1</category><question>Taking out an insurance policy against the risk of bad weather at a critical time during a project is an example of:</question><answer>Risk Transfer</answer><answer>Risk Avoidance</answer><answer>Risk Acceptance</answer><answer>Risk Reduction </answer></Q7><Q8 answer="3"><category>1</category><question>In a set of data, the most frequently occurring value is known as the:</question><answer>Mean</answer><answer>Median</answer><answer>Mode</answer></Q8><Q9 answer="4"><category>1</category><question>The technique for assessing project viability, which takes into account the time value of money, is known as:</question><answer>Earned Value Analysis</answer><answer>Monte Carlo Simulation</answer><answer>Sensitivity Analysis</answer><answer>Discounted Cash-Flow</answer></Q9><Q10 answer="4"><category>1</category><question>In project management terms, the end-product of a Monte Carlo Simulation is normally a:</question><answer>Gantt Chart</answer><answer>Network Diagram</answer><answer>S-Curve</answer><answer>Probability Distribution</answer></Q10></quiz><endtext course="3">One of the few certainties about projects is that they will involve risk and because of this those risks need to be planned for and managed in a rational and methodical manner.
This multi-media training course sets out a basic approach to the problems of identifying, quantifying and managing risk in a project environment. Many of the common techniques of both risk analysis and risk management are covered in a way which is designed to provide practical, down-to-earth guidance on this wide and varied subject.</endtext></structure>